Peter Lau

Chaoyang Qu, Beijing, China



superpeterlau@outlook.com



+8615120092341



linkedin.com/in/peterlau-rock

Summary

Enjoy Elixir/Erlang, Haskell, Rust, Emacs, Vim, and prototype design. Language and technology agnostic.

Mainly use Elixir, Ruby, Python, Node is as backend development languages.

Have ReactJS/Next.js/Frontend development experience.

Interested in distributed systems, compilation principles, type systems, serverless architecture.

Experience



Senior Software Engineer

Design Grocer

Dec 2019 - Present (2 years 9 months +)

Built backend in NodeJS/Express and frontend in ReactJS/Next.JS, TypeScript.

Design backend architecture to handle uploaded assets.

Refactored API service with Elixir/Phoenix/Absinthe

Senior Software Engineer

Seniverse

Sep 2018 - Nov 2019 (1 year 3 months)

The main business is providing API services for other companies.

Data Process Center: Our data process center based on Apache Airflow. I cleaned old code base to save 30% lines code and decouple process steps. So we could supply more data types.

Data Crawler: It was a project based on Python, Celery, Redis, RabbitMQ. I refactored it to containerize the whole project and deploy to Alibaba Cloud Kubernetes. I also did some work to rewrite the whole system in Elixir.

API service: We used Elixir to rewrite the old NodeJS service to enhance stability and avoid NodeJS-Redis-Client bugs. I was responsible for providing some of the data APIs and looked for container based Airflow alternatives. We containerized API service and deploy it to Alibaba Cloud Kubernetes. These efforts ultimately increased the system's carrying capacity and was more flexible in responding to surge API requests. After our refactor, API service brought in 30% revenue growth.

Data Analysis Dashboard: I built a data overview platform for our data scientist in Rails. This platform would monitor data process center and run some predefined formulas to tell scientist the quality of generated data.

Back End Developer

Silly Charger

Oct 2017 - Jul 2018 (10 months)

Constructed a charging services based on WeChat platform using Vanilla JS, WeChat JavaScript SDK, Laravel. We worked with local taxi companies to get users and ads income.

Meanwhile, we sold our charger on Kickstart. In order to provide better service, I built a online store to collect user mail information and accessory information in Laravel(PHP). Brought in 20% revenue growth.

Back End Developer

PalmScience

Jul 2016 - Sep 2017 (1 year 3 months)

Developed core distributed crawler system with Python, Scrapy, Scrapy-Redis, Gevent. Grabbed hundreds of millions of pieces of data every day. Analysis data on Amazon Redshift.

Built online interview system with Vue, Flask REST framework.

Education



Beijing Forestry University

Master's degree, Bioinformatics Jul 2012 - Jul 2015

Skills

Elixir • JavaScript • Ruby on Rails • Redis